# MANIMARAN SELVAN

## TECHNOPRENEUR | STRATEGIC THINKER | VISIONARY

mselvan@belyf.com | +91-994-018-1901 | https://blog.belyf.com/ | https://linkedin.com/in/maniselvan/



## **SUMMARY**

With 15+ years in software engineering and six years in technical product management, I've spearheaded initiatives in AI, cloud, and data analytics that have significantly boosted efficiency and growth. Known for high-impact strategic decision-making, and collaborative leadership, I excel in nurturing high-performing teams. I'm seeking a role to further drive tech innovation and business success.

#### AREA OF EXPERTISE

Strategic Planning, Leadership & Team Collaboration, Agile & Lean Methodologies, Continuous Improvement, Product Vision & Mission, Vendor Management, Stakeholder Management, Change Management, Software Engineering, Decision Making, Coaching/Mentoring, People Management, Cross-functional Collaboration, Conflict Resolution, Emerging Technologies

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

Java, Groovy, Javascript, Python, AWS, GCP, API Gateway, AppSync, Lambda, EventBridge, Step Functions, Gradle, Maven, Jenkins, UAT Testing, Alpha/Beta Testing, A/B Testing, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Neptune, Redis, Athena, Docker, K8s, REST, GraphQL, Git, SVN, CVS, Figma, Balsamiq, SNS, Kinesis, Kafka, Lucidchart, Draw.io, Quicksight, Grafana

#### **CERTIFICATES**

<u>Aha! Product Management Professional</u> <u>Certificate</u>

<u>freeCodeCamp – Javascript Algorithms and Data</u> <u>Structures</u>

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc Computer Science**, Bharathidasan University, Trichy, India. 2008

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Co-founded 2 startups; led IT consolidation, saving \$4.3M/year.
- Contributed to CloudFix specs, yielding \$18.3M internal and \$100M+ customer savings.
- Increased throughput 5x via SLA-driven assembly lines; authored 100+ technical specs.
- Integral in \$462M Jive acquisition, managing KT, attrition, and compliance.
- Scored top 1% in CCAT; modernized legacy software, reducing millions of LOC to 5K.
- Led architecture for 10+ software platforms; implemented cost-effective measures.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Trilogy Enterprises, Inc.

Austin, Texas (Remote)

Technical Product Manager.

Aug 2018 – Jun 2023

- Implemented 24/7 assembly lines, enabling global workforce efficiency.
- Led initiatives saving \$15M, contributing to CloudFix with \$100M in savings.
- Co-managed 60+ TPMs with retiring VP, preparing for VP role.
- Authored tech specs based on data-driven decisions.
- Developed tools for spec ordering, stack ranking, and CTO bootcamps.

#### Lead Software Engineer, Acting IT Ops Manager.

Jan 2015 - Jul 2018

- Centralized IT Ops for 5K+ global workforce, achieving 85% cost savings.
- Led 20+ senior SREs in automation and production management.
- A II LAGA IT. III
- Authored M&A IT transition playbooks.
- Coordinated with engineering leaders for unified JIRA workflow.

# Tissow Technology Ventures, LLP.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Nov 2013 – Dec 2014

- Led full-cycle architecture and development of Humingo, an e-commerce platform.
- Modernized Ticketgoose, a bus ticket booking and operator management platform, in 3 months with new tech and simplified architecture.
- Optimized tech operations for cost-effectiveness and efficiency.

# Nallan Technology Ventures Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Technical Lead.

Dec 2011 – Oct 2013

 Steered the architecture and deployment of Kachyng, a PCI-compliant mobile payment platform with single-click checkout.

## EMRG Software Solutions Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Sep 2010 – Nov 2011

(Originally from Aug 2009)

 Led a 10-member team in software engineering and SaaS, developing two financial research products.

### YuMe, Inc.

Chennai, India

Systems Engineer

Jan 2010 – Aug 2010

 Managed infrastructure and automated deployments across 6 internal environments; oversaw bi-weekly production deployments, weekly migrations, and daily DevOps tasks.

#### Java Application Developer.

Aug 2008 - Dec 2009

 Pioneered R&D in early mobile technologies and delivered native apps; created proofof-concepts in Google Web Toolkit

For a more detailed resume, please visit <a href="https://mselvan.com/?mode=comprehensive">https://mselvan.com/?mode=comprehensive</a>.